

# Aleksandar Tanevski

Website: <a href="https://atanevski.github.io">https://atanevski.github.io</a> Phone: +38975436813

### Personal statement

I am 24 years old with 2 years of working experience both in Front-end and Back-end development and currently in my last year of studies **#aculty of Computer Science and Engineering** in Skopje, Macedonia, soon to be "Bachelor of Engineering (Information technologies)".

Through my collage and work experience, I have worked on various technologies

- ASP.NET MVC with Entity Framework both Code-First and DB-First, WEB API 2, JavaScript, JQuery, Bootstrap, AJAX, HTML5, CSS3 excellent knowledge
- SQL queries, Linq, Node.js, MongoDB, UML Diagrams, TypeScript -working knowledge
- Azure, Unit testing, Angular.js, Python, Semantic Web, LESS, SASS -basic knowledge
- IDEs, Text Editors, Helpers Visual Studio, Visual Studio Code, Microsoft SQL Management Studio, ReSharper, Postman, PhoneGap
- Project Tracking and other knowledge JIRA, Asana, Trello, Agile Scrum, Slack, Rapid Application Development, Git, TFS
- Languages Macedonian (Native), English (Fluent)

Also I have directly participated in software architecture planning, creating onboarding, recruiting and Management processes and procedures.

I am hardworking, team player, dedicated, loyal, passionate about new technologies also highly motivated and interested in researching solutions to problems. I grasp new concepts and ideas quickly, highly ambitious and tend to always achieve my plans and goals.

Others are saying "You are Intermediate developer" but I declare myself as #JUNIORDEVFORLIFE because you never stop learning.

## Work experience

iVote

Full-stack Web Developer

- Back-end Development ASP.NET MVC with custom multi tier architecture
- Front-end development Bootstrap, CSS 3, JQuery, Ajax, Mustache, TypeScript
- Database modeling and realization MSSQL, Stored procedures, Optimizations
- Research and development

ITCrowd Mar 2016 — December 2016

Full-stack Web Developer

- Development software and web solutions
- Back-end Development ASP.NET MVC with Entity Framework,
- NodeJS(express), MongoDB
- Front-end development Bootstrap, CSS 3, JQuery
- Cordova cross platform experience (Phonegap) JS, CSS, HTML5
- Developing RESTful APIs
- Database modeling and realization MSSQL
- Research and development
- Managing and tutoring interns
- Involved in designing software solutions
- Involved in designing on boarding and recruitment processes

Self-employed Sep 2013 — Present

Private Tutor

- Preparing students for faculty exams
- Computer Organization and Design (Computer Arithmetic, Error-detecting codes, MIPS)
- Logic boards (Logic gates, Flip Flops, Coders, Decoders, Multiplexers and its applications)
- Algorithms (Java Collection, Synchronizations, Basic algorithms (Bubble sort, Iterating arrays)
- Front end development (CSS, HTML5, JQuery, JavaScript)
- Object oriented programming (C++, Java, C#)
- Structured programming (C)

Freelance Freelancer Mar 2015 — Dec 2015

January 2017 — Present

Freelancing as a Front-end Developer where most of the projects were customizing websites. By customizing is meant responsive designs using Bootstrap and some JS/JQuery scripts, adding plugins, features and animations with JQuery and JQuery UI, AJAX async calls, DataTables and CSS3 improvements.

## **Projects**

#### Disclosed

Lead Generation Portal

- Marketing intranet Web Application for company that works Lead generation.
- CRUD operations for campaigns, prospects, agents, user roles etc., where the accent, the complexity is on the User Experience, Database Modeling and Relationships, Data reports
- · Real-time dashboards, calculating and exporting raw data to Excel, Pdf, Csv formats
- Used technologies ASP.NET MVC, JavaScript, JQuery, MSSQL, AJAX, HTML

#### Mediawire

Cross Platform Publishing

- Publish your own magazines, newspaper, or book conveniently online. MediaWire Solutions turns your unique image and branding into a marketable medium for
  your clients and customers. We give publishers a way to represent their brand and products, expand their media presence and generate dynamic information
  about visitors and customers with our Digital Publishing Software that generates native branded apps on ios and android for Phones and Tablets.
- www.mediawiremobile.com
- My objectives were mostly bug fixing, improvements and payment processors (Stripe API)
- Used technologies Node.JS (express), MongoDB

#### **UEFA** Euro predictor

Web Application

- Web Based Application for predicting UEFA Euro 2016 from Group Stage to Final match. The player(client) predicts and interactively choose the first 3
  representations for each UEFA group. When he/she confirms the selection another screen appears to choose which 3rd placed representations proceed into
  elimination phase. The next screen is to choose the winner and enter predicted score for each bracket match. After the UEFA Euro Championship ended there
  was simple parser for the data which filtered the clients that predicted well.
- Used technologies ASP.NET MVC, MSSQL, Bootstrap, JQuery, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3

#### Amigoamigo and Deal123

E-Commerce website

- E-Commerce site where the objective of the project is to allow the user to buy products for lower prices and to apply for jobs.
- www.amigoamigo.nl , www.deal123.nl
- My objectives were mostly bug fixing and updating the Facebook API
- Used technologies ASP.NET MVC, JavaScript, JQuery, MSSQL, AJAX, HTML

#### Card reader

WPF and Web

- Access control management system for Id card/tag readers. The solution is with multi-tier architecture where the base layer is the communication with the card
  readers via serial (rs-485) communication with custom DAL. The desktop application is only for controlling and programming the card readers.
- The other part of the project is presenting the data and generating reports which is via with Web portal which communicates with the same database.
- Used technologies WPF, ASP.NET MVC, SQL, JavaScript, JQuery, MSSQL, HTML, CSS

#### Company Product

Web Api

- The project is B2B platform where helps one business to order goods or services from other business. This solution automatizes the process with digital signing and archiving the documentation and also notifies the producer, the seller and the buyer about the order.
- Used technologies ASP.NET Web Api 2 with Entity Framework, MSSQL

#### 2D Game Application

Cross platform game

- Multiplayer Cross platform app with multiple 2D Games such as Quiz, Risk (board game) and interactive "restaurant-waiter" game with multiple characters and animations. \*Disclosed app
- Used technologies ASP.NET SignalR, Cordova (PhoneGap), JavaScript, HTML5, CSS

#### Hackathon - Code Up Level Up

Windows Phone app - Ordering food

• Team project - Windows Phone 7 application which allows the user to order food from restaurants with food delivery service in Skopje, Macedonia. After choosing a restaurant, the user makes order from the menu of the restaurant. The delivery location was provided by the gps sensor of the device and the payment via credit card.

## Faculty of computer science and engineering

#### Faculty projects and courses

- Web based systems (RDF, RDFS, OWL, Semantic Web)
  - Linked data Java swing application which lists medicine from Health Insurance Fund of Macedonia (Turtle format base) and all prices from Europe of the same medicine.
- Java script
  - o Simple family tree Interactive template that allows user to generate family tree
- Visual programming C#
  - o Simple image viewer using Windows Forms
- Advanced Programming Java
- Python Programming
- Windows forms
- ASP.NET
- Advanced web development
  - o JS, Bootstrap, CSS
  - o Team project Front-end for Cisco Macedonia website
- SQL Database
- CCNA Cisco Certified Network Associate

# Education

Computer Science
Faculty of Computer Science and Engineering
Bachelor of Engineering (Information Technologies)

High School

2011 — 2016

2018 — 2011

St. Clement of Ohrid